SmartOffice AI - Complete OAuth Demo for Google Verification
This demo shows Gmail and Calendar integration with read-only OAuth scopes
Opening SmartOffice AI at www.smartoffice-ai.com
Logging in with test account: mogabli12@gmail.com
Dashboard successfully loaded - showing navigation menu
Dashboard displays: Email, Calendar, and Reports features
Now we'll demonstrate Gmail OAuth integration
Clicking "Connect Gmail" button to start OAuth flow
Google OAuth consent screen appears
Consent screen shows: "SmartOffice AI wants to access your Google Account"
App is requesting: "See and download your email messages and settings"
This is the gmail.readonly scope - READ-ONLY access only
Important: Notice there is a blue link to show detailed permissions
Clicking "See the 1 service SmartOffice AI wants to access"
Link expands to show full permission details
Gmail.readonly scope permissions displayed
Shows: "View your email messages and settings" (read-only)
Key point: The app ONLY reads emails - never sends, deletes, or modifies
Read-only access means your inbox stays completely safe and unchanged
The app uses this to categorize emails by priority (Urgent/Important/Normal)
No emails can be deleted, moved, or modified by SmartOffice AI
Now clicking "Continue" to authorize Gmail access
Authorization in progress... redirecting back to app
Gmail authorization successful!
App is now loading your Gmail inbox
Inbox successfully loaded - showing last 15 emails
Each email displays: Subject, Sender, Date, and Preview
Emails categorized with AI priority badges (when OpenAI credits available)
Gmail integration complete - all data accessed in read-only mode
Now demonstrating Google Calendar OAuth integration
Clicking "Connect Calendar" button to start Calendar OAuth flow
Google OAuth consent screen appears for Calendar
Consent screen shows Calendar access request
App requesting: "See and download any calendar you can access"
This is the calendar.readonly scope - READ-ONLY access only
Clicking the blue link to show detailed calendar permissions
Link expands to display full permission details
Calendar.readonly scope allows: See personal and shared calendars
✓ See and download calendar events and event details
✓ See email addresses of people on calendar events
✗ NO permission to create new events
✗ NO permission to edit or modify existing events
✗ NO permission to delete calendar events
This is strictly READ-ONLY access for weekly report generation
Your calendar data remains completely secure and unchanged
The app only reads event information to include in automated reports
Now clicking "Continue" to authorize Calendar access
Authorization in progress... redirecting back to app
Calendar authorization successful!
App is now loading your Google Calendar events
Calendar events successfully loaded - showing next 20 upcoming events
Each event displays: Title, Date/Time, Location, and Description
Events can be viewed directly in Google Calendar via provided links
Calendar integration complete - all data accessed in read-only mode
Optional: Showing Report Generation feature
Users can generate PDF or Word reports with email and calendar summaries
All report data comes from read-only access - no source data modifications
Security Summary: SmartOffice AI uses only read-only OAuth scopes
✓ gmail.readonly - View emails only, never send/delete/modify
✓ calendar.readonly - View events only, never create/edit/delete
Both scopes ensure complete user data privacy and security
Thank you for reviewing SmartOffice AI's OAuth implementation