SmartOffice AI - Gmail & Calendar OAuth Demo
Logging in and clicking "Connect Gmail"
Google OAuth consent screen - gmail.readonly scope
Clicking link to show detailed permissions
Gmail.readonly allows: View emails only - NO send/delete permissions
This is READ-ONLY access for email categorization
Authorizing Gmail access...
Emails successfully loaded with AI categories
Now connecting Google Calendar
OAuth consent screen - calendar.readonly scope
Showing detailed calendar permissions
Calendar.readonly: View events only - NO create/edit/delete permissions
READ-ONLY access ensures calendar data security
Authorizing Calendar access...
Calendar events successfully displayed
Both Gmail and Calendar use read-only scopes for user safety
Thank you for reviewing SmartOffice AI