SmartOffice AI - OAuth Demo for Google Verification
Logging into SmartOffice AI with test account
Dashboard loaded - Ready to connect Gmail and Calendar
Clicking "Connect Gmail" to start OAuth authorization
Google OAuth consent screen appears
App requests: "See and download your email messages and settings"
This is the gmail.readonly scope
Clicking the blue link to show detailed permissions...
Expanded permissions show gmail.readonly scope allows:
✓ View email messages and settings
✗ NO permission to send, delete, or modify emails
This is READ-ONLY access for email categorization
The app cannot make any changes to your inbox
Clicking "Continue" to authorize Gmail access...
Authorization successful - Redirecting to app...
Gmail inbox successfully loaded
Emails displayed with AI priority categories
Now connecting Google Calendar...
Clicking "Connect Calendar" button
Google OAuth consent screen for Calendar
App requests: "See and download any calendar you can access"
This is the calendar.readonly scope
Clicking to show detailed calendar permissions...
Calendar.readonly scope allows:
✓ View calendar events and details
✓ Download calendar data for reports
✗ NO permission to create, edit, or delete events
This is strictly READ-ONLY access
Your calendar data remains secure and unchanged
The app only reads events for weekly reports
Clicking "Continue" to authorize Calendar access...
Authorization successful - Loading calendar events...
Calendar events successfully displayed
Events include: title, date, time, and location
Optional: Generating weekly report...
Report includes email summaries and calendar events
All data is read-only - ensuring user privacy and security
SmartOffice AI uses only read-only OAuth scopes
Gmail.readonly and Calendar.readonly for complete data safety
Thank you for reviewing SmartOffice AI OAuth implementation